내 이름은 배리 알렌,
세상에서 가장 빠른 사나이죠.
My name is Barry Allen,
and I am the fastest man alive.
내가 어렸을 때,
엄마는 알수없는 무언가에 의해 살해당하셨죠.
When I was a child I saw my
mother killed by something impossible.
아버지는 살인 혐의로 감옥에 가셨어요.
My father went to prison for her murder.
사고로 인해 내게 있을 수 없는 일이 생겼어요.
Then an accident made me the impossible.
공식적으로는 평범한 과학수사요원이지만,
To the outside world, I'm
an ordinary forensic scientist,
비밀리에 범죄와 싸우거나,
나 같은 사람을 찾기위해 내 빠른 속도를 이용하죠.
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
and find others like me.
언젠가는 어머니를 살해한 녀석을 찾아서...
And one day, I'll find
who killed my mother...
엄마!
아버지의 누명을 벗겨드릴거에요.
Mom!
And get justice for my father.
나는 플래시에요.
I am the Flash.
플래시 지난 이야기...
Previously on The Flash...
네 이름 뭐라고 했니?
What did you say your name was again?
- 배리 알렌.
- 난 펠리시티야.
- Barry Allen.
- Felicity.
배리 뭐해?
How's Barry doing?
- 비밀인데.
- 무슨 비밀?
- It's a secret.
- What kind of secret?
넌 몰라도 되는 비밀!
The kind I have to keep.
짝사랑하는
I just have a little experience
누군가가 있어.
with liking someone who doesn't
see the same way.
- 아빠, 어떻게 된거냐 하면...
- 너희 둘 사귀는구나.
- Dad, the thing is...
- You two are dating.
- 그럼 아무렇지도 않으시네요.
- 아주 돌아버리겠다네.
- So you're not mad.
- Oh, I'm mad.
플래시맨은 쉬는 날 뭐할까요?
What does the fastest man
alive do on his day off?
번개 맞기 전에는, 종일 연구실에 있거나,
Before the lightning bolt, if I
wasn't still at the crime lab,
방콕이었죠.
I'd be at home chilling,
하지만 요즘은 아주 달라요.
but now my days off are different.
그렇게 외롭지 않죠.
Now they aren't so lonely.
번개는 내게 속도 뿐만 아니라,
The lightning didn't just give me speed.
친구도 만들어 주었죠.
It also gave me friends.
이건 대충 봐도
해부학적으로 맞지 않아.
This isn't even remotely
anatomically correct.
스노우 박사님, 요점은 그게 아닐텐데요.
That's not the point, Dr. Snow.
그럼 뭔데?
Then what is the point?
즐기는거죠.
To have fun.
게다가 다중작업을 할 수 있는
And to continue your ongoing
training by testing the speed
훈련을 계속하는 것이지.
of your mind by pushing
your ability to multitask.
웰스 박사님, 시간 지나가요~
I'm waiting on you, Dr. Wells.
182초 안에 끝내야 해.
182 seconds, gentlemen.
조심해!
뭔가 따라 붙었어.
Heads up! I think we got something.
2-11, 2-11. 강도 상황 발생!
2-11, 2-11. We're being robbed!
이봐, 진정해.
Hey, cool it.
158초 밖에 안남았어.
158 seconds to go.
체크메이트!
Checkmate.
- 잠깐만요, 체크메이트라구요?
- 그래.
- Wait, checkmate?
- Checkmate.
배워야할 것들이 있는 것 같은데...
I guess we still have
a few things left to learn,
안그런가, 알렌군?
don't we, Mr. Allen?
콜린즈 4번가에 무장강도야.
Armed robbery at 4th and Collins.
공식적으로 말하지만, 수술게임과
탁구는 내가 이겼어요.
For the record, I crushed it
in operation and ping pong.
보기보단 쉽지않다구요.
It's not as easy as it looks.
헉~
Ugh!
가까운 병원이 어디지?
Where's the nearest hospital?
성 앤드류병원인데...
북쪽으로 7블럭. 동쪽으로 2블럭이야.
St. Andrews...
Seven blocks north, two east.
총상 환자가 있다고 응급실에 알려.
Call the ER, tell them
they have an incoming GSW.
이동해. 이쪽 길 모두
Let's go. I want this locked up all the way
봉쇄하도록.
to the end of the block.
견인차는 도난당했구요.
Tow truck was stolen.
성 앤드류 병원에 있는 총상
입은 운전자는 안정적이라는데,
Driver of the armored car
is in a stable condition
어떻게 왔는지는 모른답니다.
at St. Andrews, and no one's
exactly sure how he got there.
감시카메라 확인했나?
Did you check the security cameras?
하드드라이브를 빼갔어요.
Camera's storage drive was stolen.
전문털이범들 같아요.
Guys are pros.
그래도, 녀석들이 노렸던
Everything's still here,
칸다크 왕조의 다이아몬드를 포함해서
including what I think they were after,
모든게 남아있네.
the Kahndaq dynasty diamond.
시립박물관에 전시될 예정이었지.
It was on its way to central
city museum for exhibition.
맞아요, 아이리스가 같이 가자고 했어요.
Right, Iris is trying
to talk me into going.
전 그렇게 박물관을 좋아하지 않지만,
I'm not much of a museum guy,
그녀가 아주 가고싶어...
but when she really wants to do something...
하던 일이나 마저 할께요.
I'm just going to walk away now.
죄송합니다. 반장님.
친구 때문에...
Sorry, captain. I was at the hospital
- 병원에 갔다 오느라...
- 잃어버린 물건은 없네.
- visiting a friend.
- There's nothing missing.
누군가 방해를 한 모양이야.
It looks like someone
interrupted a robbery.
경비 말로는 세놈이 있었다는군.
Guard says there was three of them.
사실, 넷이었어요.
Actually, there was four.
제말은, 제가 이런 짓을 한다면
I mean, that's how many I would bring
넷이 필요하다는 얘기죠.
if I were doing a robbery of this nature.
저건 분명 4인승 트럭이구요.
That's definitely a four guy truck.
운전자에, 경비를 해치울 두 녀석에...
A driver, two more
to cover the guards, and...
액화질소로 문을 박살낸 녀석,
Somebody used liquid nitrogen
to crack open this door,
이렇게 넷이죠.
so four bad guys.
명석한 통찰력에 고맙네, 알렌군.
Thank you, Mr. Allen,
for your brilliant insight.
누군가에겐 아주 빠르겠지만,
For somebody so fast,
자네에겐 즉흥적으로 하는 것도 아주 느리겠군.
you're a little slow on the improvising.
뭐 아무거라도 본게 있나?
Did you see anything that could
help us catch these guys?
네, 한 녀석이 마스크를 벗었는데,
Yeah, one of them lost his mask.
녀석의 얼굴을 봤죠.
I saw his face.
놈을 알아볼 수 있는지
So look through these mug shots
of Central City's most wanted,
현상수배범 명단을 살펴보게.
and see if you can find our guy.
이자에요.
That's him.
이런~
Damn.
레오나드 스나트
Leonard Snart.
바슬로뮤에 버금갈만큼 나쁘다는
레오나드 말이에요?
Leonard? That's almost
as bad as Bartholomew.
스나트 역시 섹시하진 않아.
Snart ain't sexy, either.
스나트의 아버지도 경찰이었는데...
Snart's father was a cop...
나쁜 경찰이었지.
Was a bad cop.
아동학대로 감옥에 갔지.
Took his anger out on his kids
until he went to prison.
스나트의 아버지도 감옥에 있다구요?
Snart's dad's in prison too?
모임 하나 만들어야겠네요.
We should start a club.
그는 6개월에 한번씩 나타나.
He shows up, like, every six months.
일주일 정도 모의를 하고,
He cases a job for weeks
before he makes his move.
일이 끝나면, 사라지지.
Then, he does the job... Gets away.
그건 스트릭이 밖에 없었을 때 얘기죠.
That's before The Streak was around.
방금 딴 사람 얘기하는 것처럼 말했니?
Did you just refer to yourself
in the third person?
딱히 떠오르는게 없어
스트릭이라고 했지만...
I referred to The Streak,
which I'm pretty sure I can top.
새로운 이름을 생각해봤는데,
I've been thinking of a new name.
이거 어때요? 플래...
What do you think about The Fla...
커피 마시세요.
Coffee break.
센트럴 시티 최고의 커피를
Thought I would bring
Central City's finest java
가져왔어요.
over to Central City's finest.
고맙지만, 카페인 끊었다.
Thanks. I'm off caffeine.
에디와의 사이를 아신 이후로
My dad's been mad
at me every since I told him
줄곧 저러셔.
about me and Eddie.
아니, 네가 거짓말해서 저러시는 것 같은데.
No, you mean he's mad at you
because you didn't tell him.
우선은 아빠 편드는 것 처럼 들리네.
Uh, first, that sounds
like you're taking his side,
그리고 아빠가 저러시는게
"말을 안한다는게 아니라,"
and second, do you know
how he does this whole,
"어떻게 돌아가는지 살펴보고난 후에 보자"
?쏧'm not talking to you,
but I have a whole bag
라는 뜻으로 그러는거야.
"full of judgmental looks
I'm gonna try out on you later??
그렇겠지, 나도 그렇게 받아들일때 까지
yeah, I've been on the receiving end
시간이 걸리긴 했지만 말이야.
of those a few times.
소통에 대해 말하자면,
Speaking of communications,
혹은 불통이든,
결국은 모두 언론계의 문제라는 거지.
or lack thereof, after all
of these journalism classes,
- 좋은 생각이 있는데.
- 뭔데?
- I got an idea.
- Huh.
블로그를 시작했어.
I started a blog.
좋아, 뭐에 대한거야?
아시다시피 대놓고 떠들어대진 않겠지만
All right, what's it about?
Your brownie obsession?
네가 먹은 브라우니옵세션에 관한거야?
'Cause, you know, you probably
shouldn't broadcast that.
아니, 뭔가 중요한거야.
No, something important.
스트릭에 대해 센트럴시티가 알아야할 그 무엇말이야.
Something that Central City
needs to know about, The Streak.
그가 밖에 있다구, 배리.
He's out there, Barry.
소문에 의하면, 그가 무장강도를 막았대.
Rumor has it, he stopped
an armed car robbery earlier.
살펴볼 파일좀 가져갔으면 하는데...
I was hoping that I could take
a look at the file, and...
뭐라는거야? 진행중인 사건에 대해
What? I'm not at liberty
너랑 자유토론할 권리는 내게 없거든.
to discuss an ongoing police
investigation with you.
언제부터 그랬는데, 수다쟁이씨?
Since when, Mr. Blabbermouth?
불가능한 사건에 대해 조사할 기회를
Take it from someone who's been
빼았겼던 11살 때 부터지.
investigating the impossible
since they were 11.
이것에 블로그를 시작하게되면,
Blogging about this is
오만잡것들이 대문앞에 쌓일거야.
only gonna bring the crazies
to your front door.
내 블로그는 익명이거든.
My blog is anonymous.
알았어. 하지만 익명이든 아니든 안전하지 않아.
All right, well, anonymous
or not, it's not safe.
얼마나 괴상한 녀석들이 인터넷을
You never know what kind
of weirdos are out there
떠도는지 넌 상상도 못할거야.
trolling on the internet.
그건 내가 보장하지.
I can vouch for that.
인터넷은 정신병자에 일베충이들로 가득하지.
The internet is full of
weirdos and nerd rage...
점점 더 많아지고 있어.
Lots and lots of nerd rage.
안녕, 펠리시티 스모크야.
Hi. Felicity Smoak.
난 아이리스 웨스트.
Iris West.
배리 알렌.
Barry Allen.
그치만 서로를 잘 알고 있을 걸.
펠리시티는...
But you both already knew that.
Felicity is...
스탈링시티에서 알게되었다는
The girl that you met in Starling City,
아가씨, 맞지?
the computerer, right?
배리의 이상한 사건에 대해
너희 둘이 조사하는거야?
You two worked on one
of Barry's unexplainable cases.
요약하자면 그렇지.
Which, long story short,
was definitely explainable.
그니까 번개가 이쪽으로 내리쳤단 말이지?
So the lightning came through here?
그래.
Yeah.
지난 몇 주 동안 떠도는 소문이 있어.
There's been some rumors
the last few weeks.
거리를 가로지르는 붉은 흔적들을 목격했데.
People seen a red blur
tearing through the streets.
그게 무슨 소리야?
What the hell is it, man?
아마도 무인비행기거나,
Maybe it was a drone.
일급 군사무기겠지.
Some top secret army thing.
어렸을때 말이야, 할아버지는 나와 누나를
When I was a kid, my grandfather used to
자동차식당에 데려가곤 했는데.
take my sister and me
to this diner, the motorcar.
음식은 형편없었지만, 센트럴시티 전경을
Food was for crap, but the view was great,
바라보는 경치는 끝내줬지.
right across from
the Central City precinct.
난 여전히 그곳에 가서, 녀석들의 무전을 듣고,
I still go there. I listen to their radios.
응답시간을 체크하곤 해.
I learn their response times.
센트럴시티에 40개의 은행이 있는데,
There are 40 banks in Central City,
경찰 출동시간은 60초 걸려.
each of them within 60 seconds
of police response.
움직이는 목표물을 이용하는 장점은 말이야.
That's the advantage
of hitting a moving target.
호송차량이 911에 신고를 하면,
Once the armored car called 911,
경찰이 도착하기 까지 182초가 걸려.
we had 182 seconds before
any cop could be on the scene.
누구도 우릴 막을 수 없지.
No one could have gotten there
fast enough to stop us.
그런데 누군가 막았는데,
But something did,
넌 이성을 잃었지.
and you lost your cool.
너도 규칙을 알잖아.
You know the rules.
불가피한 경우가 아니라면
경찰이나 경비는 쏘지 않는다는 거 말이야.
We don't shoot guards or cops
unless it's the only option.
쉽게 흥분하는 녀석들은 필요없어.
We don't need the heat.
흥분한다고?
The heat?
블러가 뭐라고 생각하는데, 엉?
What the hell do you think
the blur is, Snart?
그래, 바보같은 짓이야.
Right. Screw this.
너도 망칠거야.
난 빠지겠어.
Screw you. I'm out.
그래, 빠지겠다면 빠져.
Well, if you're out, you're out.
그 녀석은 사람이야.
This blur is a man.
우린 우리만의 게임을 해야지.
We're gonna have to up our game.
아이리스는 좋은 사람 같아.
Iris seems very nice.
그리고 완전 예쁘잖아.
And really pretty. Like, super pretty.
축하해.
Congratulations.
글쎄, 아이리스는 내 여자친구가 아니야.
Well, Iris isn't my girlfriend.
남자친구가 있는 그냥 친구일 뿐이야.
She's just a friend
who actually has a boyfriend.
오, 것 참....관심 땡기네,
Oh, that's... Interesting,
내 생각이야.
I guess.
여긴 왜 온거야?
What are you really doing here?
널 보게 되서 좋기는 하지만,
I mean, it's good to see you,
너와 올리버는 해야할 일인가 뭔가 있잖아.
but do you and Oliver need something, or...
아니, 아니, 그냥 너 보고싶어서 온거야.
No, no, I came because I wanted to see you.
혼수상태에 빠졌었다고 들었거든.
I heard you were out of the coma.
전화도 못하고, 편지도 못쓰고,
Didn't call, didn't write,
달리지도 못하고....
didn't race over...
올리버가 그렇게 말했어?
Oliver told you?
사실은, 그날 밤 스탈링시티 옥상에서
Honestly, I heard you two talking
둘이 말하는 것을 들었는데.
on that rooftop
in Starling City that night.
그거 보고싶었어.
I want to see it.
아니, "그거"는 네 속도를 말하는거야.ㅋ
And by ?쐇t,??I mean your speed,
내가 떠벌리고 다닐거라고 생각한다면
in case you thought I was
talking about something else,
- 그렇지 않아. 절대로....
- 알겠어.
- which I... which I was not.
- Okay.
음, 저기 건물 보이지?
Okay, you see that building?
응.
Uh-huh.
눈 크게 뜨고 봐.
Keep your eyes on it.
우~후!
Whoo-hoo!
와우~
Whoa.
저 건물 옥상에서
You took a picture of me?
내 사진 찍은거야?
From the top of that building?
그럼, 인스타그램엔 올리지 말구.
Yeah. Don't instagram that.
헐~ 대박~
Unbelievable.
네 신발에서 연기가 나.
Your shoes are smoking.
괘...괜찮아.
종종 있는 일이야.
That... that's fine.
It's... it happens sometimes.
마찰방지 신발을 신고 있거든.
It's why I have a friction-proof suit.
어디서 난건데?
Where did you get that?
보여줄게.
I'll show you.
The FLASH
▒ REMEMBER 0416 ▒
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
이곳에서 경찰 주파수를 감청해
범죄가 일어나는지 살피고 있어.
And this is where my team monitors the
police bands for criminal activity.
시에서 일어나는 일들은 다 알수 있지.
We can track anything
that's happening in the city.
이거 봐바.
Check this out.
우린 독자위성을 갖고 있어.
We've got our own satellite.
나도 알지.
I know.
나도 가끔 이곳을 해킹하거든.
I've hacked into it from time to time.
- 바보.
- 물론...
- Rude.
- It is, of course,
다시 만나서 반가워, 펠리시티.
so wonderful to see you again, Felicity.
실은 우리 일에 대해
I'm just wondering
얼마나 알려줘야 할지 걱정이야.
how much of our operation
she needs to know about.
저도 비밀 하나는 잘 지켜요.
I'm really good at keeping secrets.
맞아요, 펠리시티는 애로우와 함께 일해요.
Yeah, Felicity works with The Arrow.
- 대단해.
- 너랑은 확실히 아니지.
- Sweet.
- And you apparently are not.
이제 말이 되네.
Now it's all making sense.
애로우가 누군지 알고 있죠?
You know who The Arrow is.
잠깐, 너도 알고 있어?
Wait, do you know who The Arrow is?
글쎄...
Uh...
우리 팀도 비슷한 처지라고 말해두지뭐.
Let's just say that my team
has a similar set up,
뾰족한 물건들이 많은 것만 빼고 말이야.
but with... More pointy objects.
스모크양 어서와요.
Welcome, Ms. Smoak.
웰스 박사님?
Dr. Wells?
바로 그 유명한 웰스 박사님이세요?
The Dr. Wells?
그냥 해리슨이라고 불러요.
Please, call me Harrison, Felicity.
와우, 절 아세요?
Oh, you know who I am?
국가 정보기술경쟁에서
Ranked second in
2위에 올랐고,
the national informative
technology competition
19살에
at age 19,
MIT에서 사이버 보안 및 컴퓨터 과학
graduated M.I.T. With masters degree
석사학위를 받았지.
in cyber security and computer sciences.
그 정도는 알지.
I know who you are.
내가 눈여겨 보고 있는 과학분야 인재가
I keep an eye out for promising
talent in scientific fields.
씨스코, 케이틀린
It's what brought me Cisco, Caitlin,
그리고 펠리시티 자네지.
and I foresaw great things from you.
대단한 일 얘기 나와서 말인데,
Speaking of great things,
한 번 볼래?
want to see something cool?
얼마나 빨리 달릴 수 있어요?
How fast can he run?
이론적으로 말하자면,
He hasn't reached his top speed yet,
아직도 최고 속도에는 한참 멀었어.
theoretically speaking.
정말 괜찮아요?
So is he really okay?
심박수는 정상범위야.
His heart rate is
within normal range for him.
아뇨, 내 말은, 번개가 그를 변화시켰는데,
No, I mean, the lightning bolt changed him.
어느 정도 알고 계시나 해서요.
Do any of you really know how much?
알 만큼은 알고 있지.
We know a fair amount.
그에게 뭐든지 빨리 지나가는데,
If everything about him is sped up,
빨리 늙어버릴까요?
is he going to age faster?
그가 아주 빨리 달리면 무슨 일이 벌어질까요?
What would happen if he ran too fast?
내 말은, 그는 휙~하고 지나가버리는데,
I mean, would he just
be running, and then, poof,
빨간 먼지 흔적만 남는 거잖아요.
he's dust in a red costume?
배리 알렌을 보호하기 위해서
Everything we do here at S.T.A.R. Labs
스타랩에 모든 것을 갖추고 있네.
is to protect Barry Allen.
우릴 믿게, 그는 아주 잘 적응하고 있어.
Trust us, Felicity,
he is in very good hands here.
뒤로 가는 거 볼래?
Want to see how fast I can run backwards?
걱정하지마, 금방 나아져.
Don't worry. He heals quickly too.
어, 이해가 안되네.
Eh, I don't get it.
스나트가 여기에 왜 올까요?
Why would snart come here?
스나트는 지난번 저지당했지만,
Snart's been deterred before,
뭔가 원하는게 있다면,
but once he goes after something,
얻기 전까지는 절대 멈추지 않아.
he doesn't stop until he gets it, ever.
죠, 아이리스와 진지하다는 거 알아주세요.
Joe, I want you to know that
I'm really serious about Iris.
정말 굉장한 여자에요,
난 사랑에 빠져있는 내 자신을...
She's an amazing woman,
and I can really see myself...
내가 대학 마지막날 있었던
I ever tell you about that wild night
광란의 밤 얘기 했었던가?
I had my last day of college?
안한것 같은데요. 그렇죠?
I don't think so. No?
퇴근하고 술독에 빠졌었던 얘기는?
Not even after we kicked back
a few beers after work?
우리 그런 적 없잖아요.
We've never done that.
맞아, 그렇지.
Oh, right.
그런 일들은 내 친구들이나 같이 하는 거지.
That's the things I do with my friends,
그런 일들이 없었다는 것은
우리가 친구가 아니란 얘기고.
and since we've never done
those things we ain't friends.
그러니 자네 연애사를
So there's actually no reason
알아야 할 이유는 더더욱 없는거지.
I need to know about your dating life.
난 아이리스와의 개인적인 문제로 인해서
I just don't want my personal relationship
공적인 관계를 망치고 싶진 않아요.
with your daughter to affect
our working relationship.
자네 때문이 아니야,
딸 때문에 그러지.
It ain't about you, Eddie. It's about her.
자네와 아이리스에 대한
얘기를 하지 않는다면
So as long as we don't talk
about you and her,
아~무 문제 없네.
we will be cool.
라디오나 듣는게 좋겠군요.
Maybe we should just listen to the radio.
When a man loves a woman~
(남자가 여자를 사랑할 때...ㅋ)
When a man loves a woman
Let's get it on~
(내 손을 잡아요~ㅋㅋㅋ)
let's get it on
조용한게 좋죠.
Quiet is good.
- 고마워.
- 아니야.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
안녕~ 너희 둘...
Hey, you two.
- 안녕.
- 우린 둘이 아닌데.
- Hey.
- We're not a two.
오, 아니야. 우린 따로 따로야.
Oh, no. We are a one and one.
그래.
Yeah.
배리랑 시내구경 잘했어?
Has Barry been showing you
some of the sights in Central City?
그럼, 굉장했어.
Yes, I have seen some
pretty amazing things.
정말?
Really?
그럼, 시간이 좀 된다면 말이야,
Well, if you've got some time,
센트럴시의 화려한 밤문화도 볼 수 있는데 말이야.
maybe we can show you some
of Central City's night life.
그건 안돼.
Oh, no.
스탈링시의 밤문화만으로도 벅차거든.
I get plenty of night life
in Starling City.
하지만 이것 만큼은 놓치고 싶지 않을걸.
Oh, this is something that
I don't think that
you're gonna want to miss.
지터스에서의 하찮은 밤.
Trivia night at Jitters.
에디도 별 기대는 안해. 인정해.
Eddie's not really excited
about it, I admit.
하지만 우리들의 밤이 될거야.
But it could be our night, guys.
우리의 밤이 75달러 카푸치노 값어치는 있겠지?
Our night to win $75 worth of cappuccinos.
헐, 비싸다.
Uh, yum.
별 일 없는지 확인전화 하고 올께.
You know what, I'm gonna go call work,
check in, make sure everything's okay.
얼마 걸리지 않을거야.
I'll be back in a second.
- 왜 이러는 건데?
- 뭘 말이야?
- Why are you doing this?
- Doing what?
너와 에디의 하찮은 밤에
The trivia night with you and Eddie,
억지로 쌍쌍 데이트하는 것 같잖아.
forcing this whole double date thing.
펠리시티가 괜찮은 여자이고,
Because that girl is great,
사랑스런 공부벌레와 어울린만한 사람이
and she happens to come
from your very rare species
흔치않아서 그렇지.
of adorable nerds.
그녀에 대해 더 알려주는 건 어때?
Why didn't you tell me more about her?
더 이상 알려줄게 없는데.
There's nothing to tell.
그냥 친구라구.
She's just a friend.
여자들은 좋아하지도 않는 사람을 보려고
Barry, girls don't just hop on trains
그냥 그렇게 단순하게
and travel hundreds of miles
기차타고 수백마일을 오지는 않아.
to see someone that they don't like.
봐, 이게 바로 내 도움이 필요한 이유야.
See, this is why you need my help.
오늘밤 데리고 나와.
Bring her tonight.
재밌을거야.
We'll have fun.
퍽도 재미지겠다.
Yeah, fun.
아주 정교한 장치를 구하셨잖아요.
You wanted state of the art, Snart.
여기 가져왔어요.
I bring you state of the art, my good sir.
- 이딴게 뭐지?
- 겉보기와는 달라요.
- What's this?
- It might not look like much,
표지로 책을 판단하지 말라는 말 아시죠?
but never judge a book
by its cover, you know?
가연성 액체 연료가 고농축으로 연소하게되면,
Fires highly concentrated,
combustible liquid fuel
공기와 접촉한 모든 것을 태우죠.
that ignites on contact with the air.
뜨겁게 만드는 것 따위는 필요치 않아.
I don't need to heat things up.
속도를 줄일만한 게 필요하지.
I need to slow them down.
바로 그거에요.
That's the one, then.
상자 안에 있어요.
You were drawn right to it.
스타랩에서 훔친건데,
Stolen from S.T.A.R. Labs
after the incident,
기계실 내부에 경비라고는
and with nothing
but a skeleton security crew
해골바가지 밖에 없더라구요.
to guard the tech inside.
뭔가 물질이 방출되는데 뭔지는 모르겠어요.
Emits some sort of substance.
I'm not sure what it is.
흰색 불꽃인데 뜨겁지는 않고 차가워요.
Like a white flame,
but it's not hot, it's cold.
덤으로 안경이 있는데
Glasses look like they're made
of the same tech.
뭐에 쓰는 물건이지?
What are they for?
눈부심 때문이죠.
The glare. You'll see.
이 일 누가 또 알고 있지?
Who else knows you took this?
우리 뿐이에요.
Just us.
아니, 나 혼자지.
No, just me.
미안하군 친구.
Sorry, pal.
여러분, 하찮은 상을 받으실 분 있나요?
Party people, who's ready
to get their trivia on?
네, 여기 새로운 도전자가 있습니다.
Okay, everybody, welcome.
We've got some new challengers.
e=mc해머, 박수로 맞아주세요.
Please, welcome e=mc Hammer.
다들 알겠지만, E=mc 스퀘어는
No, you see, I did it because E=mc squared
아인쉬타인의 운동에너지 공식인데
is Einstein's formula
for kinetic energy, right?
"유 캔 터치 디스"라니....ㅋㅋㅋ
And, you know, can't touch this.
그건 그렇구, 배리.
That's great, Barry.
펠리시티는 어디 있어?
So where is Felicity?
모르겠는데.
I'm not sure.
시작 시간을 말해주긴 했는데...
I told her it started at...
드레스를 입는 거야 뭐 자유지.
Feel free to buy yourself that dress.
하찮은 밤인데 의상이 과했나?
I totally overdressed for trivia night.
아니야, 정말 멋져.
No, you look amazing.
그래 맞아.
Yeah, you do.
E=mc 해머.
E=mc hammer.
정말 웃기다.
That's funny.
봤지?
See?
대륙횡단 철도가 놓인 1852년 까지는
It wasn't until 1852,
축산업으로 번성했던 이 도시는
when the transcontinental
railroad laid their tracks
공식적으로 시로 인정받지는
through this thriving cattle town,
않았습니다.
that we became officially incorporated.
같은 해에, 전무후무한 홍수가 범람했죠.
That same year, the worst flood
this area's ever seen hit.
하지만 그런 재앙속에서 영웅이 있었습니다.
But from that disaster rose
Central City's greatest hero,
바비네 목장주였던 "보빈 맥필리".
cattle rancher Bobby ?쏝ovine??Mcfeely.
보빈 맥필리는 홍수 속에서 17마리의 소를 구했어요.
Bovine Mcfeely saved 17 cows
from the great flood.
안녕, 꼬마야, 껌 줄까?
Hey, kid. Gum?
지금 보시게 될 전시물은
And now, for the exhibit
가까이 와서 보셔야 하는데,
I'm sure you've all come here to see,
칸다크 왕조의 다이아몬드입니다.
the historic Kahndaq dynasty diamond.
조심하세요. 너무 가까히 다가가면
Be careful. Get too close
근접 센서를 건들어 경보가 울리게 됩니다.
and you'll set off the proximity alarms.
그래선 안되겠지?
Wouldn't want to do that.
- 파스퇴르가 셋이고.
- 으응.
- Three is Pasteur.
- Mm-mm.
에델이 셋, 파스퇴르가 넷이면.
Three is Erdel, and four is Pasteur.
- 맞아.
- 다섯이면?
- Right.
- Five?
- 데카르트.
- Descartes.
쟤네들 영어로 말하는 거 맞아?
Are they even speaking English?
자, E=mc해머 팀이 점수 얻었습니다.
And the points go to E=mc Hammer.
너희 둘 잘해낼거라고 알고 있었지.
I knew you two would make a good team.
그래, 펠리시티는 무슨 일 해?
So, Felicity, what do you do?
컴퓨터 과학자에요.
I work in computer sciences
- 퀸 그룹에서 일하죠.
- 정말?
- at Queen Consolidated.
- Really?
스탈링시티에 남자친구 있어?
Do you have a boyfriend in Starling City?
아니, 아니, 아무도 없어.
No, no, there is no one.
마실 거 좀 가져올게.
I'll get us some more drinks.
나도 너무 많이 마셨나보다.
And I had too many of those first ones,
금방 다녀올게.
so I will be right back.
- 왜?
- 빼기는?
- What?
- Dude.
빼다니, 뭐...
Dude? Wha...
아직도 그녀의 마음을 모른다고 할거야.
Are you still gonna tell me
that she's not into you?
저 옷 입은 것 좀 봐.
Look at that dress.
그녀에게 남자친구 있나구 물었을 때
And when I asked her
the boyfriend question,
멈짓했지.
she froze.
그점에 있어선 넌 참 약아빠졌어.
Yeah, you were
particularly sly with that one.
펠리시티는 똑똑하고, 친절하고, 예쁘기까지해.
Felicity is smart, nice, and pretty.
게다가 가장 중요한 것은, 내가 입버릇 처럼 말했던
And most importantly, she is the first girl
"굉장한 너"를 인정해주고
at I have seen you with
that really understands
너를 잘 이해해주는
and appreciates you for the amazing person
첫 여자라는 거야.
that I am always telling you that you are.
네게 완벽한 여자야.
She's perfect for you,
뭘 더 망설이는거야, 배리?
so what are you waiting for, Barry?
얼마동안 사라진건가?
How long has it been missing?
잘 모르겠어요.
I don't know.
다시 한 번 물어보지, 씨스코.
I'm gonna ask you again, Cisco.
하지만, "잘 모르겠어요"란
But when I do,
대답보다 더 확실한 답이 필요할거야.
I expect a more specific answer
than ?쏧 don't know.??
자, 이 무기가 사라진지 얼마나 지났나?
now, how long has this weapon been gone?
하루 이틀 쯤이요.
A day, maybe two.
오늘 아침 관리인중 한명이 안보 이는데,
One of the janitors didn't
show up for work this morning.
아마도 그 사람이 가져갔을거에요.
He was probably the one who took it.
도난당할 것이라고는 생각하지...
I didn't think that...
그래 생각하지 못했지,
You didn't think,
이론적으로 누군가를, 특히 배리 알렌을
because if you had, you would
have discussed with me
다치게 할 수도 있는 뭔가를
first your desire to build
something that could,
만들고 싶을 때
in theory, hurt anyone,
나랑 상의했어야 했다는 생각 말이네.
and in particular, Barry Allen.
죄송해요.
I'm sorry.
설명할 기회를 주신다면...
If you just let me explain...
이 무기에 대한 내 생각을 알고 싶나, 씨스코.
You know how I feel about weapons, cisco.
더 이상 스타랩에 있지 않아.
They do not belong in S.T.A.R. Labs.
그러니 어디에 있는지 알아내야 할 거야.
Now, you are gonna figure out
a way to locate this gun,
그것도 지금 당장 말이야.
and you are gonna do it right now.
네가 만든게 정확히 뭘 할 수 있어?
This thing you built, what can it do?
아주 안좋아.
Bad stuff.
수상한 녀석이 발견되면 전화하라고 하셨죠.
You said to call if there
was anything suspicious.
이 녀석이 두번이나 다녀갔어요.
This guy went through the tour twice.
아무나 그렇게하지는 않죠.
Nobody does that.
웨스트 형사다.
This is Detective West.
박물관에 레오나드가 있다.
I have a visual on
Leonard Snart at the museum.
즉시 지원요청 바란다.
Requesting immediate back up.
미안해, 아는 문제인 것 같아서,
I'm sorry. I thought I knew it,
흥분되어....그냥 눌러버렸네.
and I got excited, and I... I just hit it.
괜찮아, 다른 사람들도 역시 틀릴거야.
No, I mean, maybe they'll get it wrong too.
그래 맞아, 프라이드 앤 파다완스팀도
Oh, yeah. I am sure that the team
한솔로의 우주선 이름은
named Pride and Padawans
doesn't know the name
알지 못할거야.
to Han Solo's ship.
이런, 자기야.
황당한 표정이 너무 귀엽더라.
Oh, honey, you are so cute
when you're confused.
스나트를 찾았대.
Someone spotted snart.
가봐야겠어.
- I gotta go.
- I'll cover for you.
대충 둘러댈께.
뭐라고 할건데?
All right, what are you gonna say?
보통은 클럽에서 올리버가 다른 여자랑 있었다거나
I usually tell people Oliver's
at a night club with a girl
만취한 올리버를 돌봐줬다고 둘러대는데...
or nursing a hangover.
나 한텐 안통할거야.
None of which will work for me.
심한 복통에다가 설사까지 한다고 하지뭐.
Bad stomach ache... Really bad diarrhea.
썩 유쾌한 변명거리는 아니네.
Yeah, I'm not comfortable with that excuse.
가기나 해.
Just go.
조심하고.
Stay safe.
미친년처럼 지금 허공에다 얘기한거야?
And I'm talking to air now, which is odd.
지금도 그러네...
And I'm still doing it.
스나트!
Snart!
- 괜찮나?
- 으읔, 타는 것 같이 아파요.
- You okay?
- Ahh, aah, it burns.
무기 성능 시험할 시간이군.
Time for a test run.
얼마나 빠른지 보자구.
Let's see how fast you are.
카!
Gah!
안돼!
No!
안돼.
No.
여전히 감각이 없어.
It's still numb.
3도 동화상을 입은 것 같아.
It's presenting itself
like third degree frostbite.
바로 치유되는 것으로 아는데...
I thought he had hyper healing.
이번엔 아주 느려.
It's been slowed.
세포가 제때에 재생되지 않았다면,
If your cells weren't
regenerating at the rate
혈관이 딱딱하게 굳어버려
they are, your blood vessels
would have frozen solid
영구 신경손상을 입었을거야.
and the nerve damage
would have been permanent.
살아있는게 행운이야.
You're lucky to be alive.
스나트는 여타 변형인간이 아니에요.
Snart wasn't another meta-human.
어떤 총을 가지고 있었는데.
He has some kind of gun.
물건들을 얼려 미끄러지게 만들어요.
It froze things, slowed me down...
사람들을 구할 시간이 충분치 않았어요.
Enough that I wasn't in time
to save someone.
기록에 따르면,
According to his record,
스나트는 고등학교를 중퇴했는데,
Snart didn't even bother
to finish high school,
어떻게 최첨단 무기를 만들 수 있지?
so how did he build a handheld
high tech snow machine?
스타랩이 만들었다네.
S.T.A.R. Labs built the cold gun.
웰스 박사님과 케이틀린은 상관없는 일이야.
Dr. Wells and Caitlin
had nothing to do with this.
내가 만들었어.
I built the gun.
네가 만들었다고?
You did?
왜?
Why?
속도와 추위는 상극인데...
Because speed and cold are opposites.
열은 원자가 얼마나 빨리
Temperature is measured
흔들리느냐에 따라 측정돼.
by how quickly the atoms
of something are oscillating.
빨라질수록, 뜨거워질수록,
The faster they are, the hotter it is,
원자 수준은 낮아지고 차가워지지.
and when then are cold, they're
slower on the atomic level.
그리고나선 움직임이 전혀 없게 되고,
이른바...
When there's no movement at all,
it's called...
절대영.
Absolute zero.
맞아.
Yeah.
절대영을 만들기위해 소형 냉동엔진을 만들었는데,
I designed a compact cryo engine
to achieve absolute zero.
널 저지하게 위해 그런거야.
I built it to stop you.
그땐 너에 대해 잘 몰랐어, 배리.
I didn't know who you were then, Barry.
난 네가 마든이나 님버스 처럼 괴물로
I mean, what if you turned out
to be some psycho,
변할 수도 있다고 생각했어.
like Mardon or Nimbus?
하지만 안그랬잖아. 응?
But I didn't. Did I?
우린 좋은 일을 하기 위해
안벽한 건물을 지었는데,
We built the entire structure
you're standing in to do good,
몽땅 날라가 버렸어.
and it blew up.
그런 상황에서 최악의 경우를 대비한
In the wake of that,
you can understand why Cisco
씨스코를 이해해야지.
would want to be prepared for the worst.
그건 이해하겠는데, 이해할 수 없는 것은...
I can understand that,
but what I can't understand
내게 말하지 않은 이유에요.
is why you didn't tell me what you did.
지금까지 함께하면서
I mean, after all we've been through,
날 믿었다고 생각했어요.
I thought you trusted me.
- 우린 친구라고 생각했다구요
- 친구 맞아, 배리.
- I thought we were friends.
- We are, Barry.
내게 언급이라도 해줬다라면
I mean, if you would have just told me,
준비를 했을 거라구요.
I could have been prepared.
대신에, 오늘밤 누군가 죽었어요.
But instead, someone died tonight.
그 점은 내가 평생 떠안을 짐이야.
And I have to live with that.
아니, 씨스코, 우리 모두의 짐이지.
No, Cisco. We all do.
시내 극장에서 벌어진 잔인하고
Theatergoers remain shaken
무시무시한 공격에서 살아남은 연극관람객들은
after surviving tonight's
brutal and bizarre attack
충격에 빠져있습니다.
저 뉴스...별일 없으시죠?
in a downtown theater...
The news... Are you okay?
난 괜찮다.
I'm fine.
도대체 언제까지 이러실거에요?
How long is this gonna go on?
냉랭한 분위기가 계속 이어질 것 같은데...
Seems like the cold treatment
is going around.
나중에 얘기하자, 아이리스, 제발.
Not now, Iris, please.
아니, 지금해요.
Yes, now.
상의 없이 경찰대학 원서를 넣었을 때도
You did the same thing
when I tried to sign up
아빠는 이러셨어요.
for the police academy without telling you.
내가 지쳐 원서를 찢어버릴 때까지
You didn't speak to me for weeks...
몇 주 동안 말씀 한마디 안하셨죠.
Not until I withdrew my application.
하지만, 이번엔 절대 양보못해요, 아빠.
Well, I am not withdrawing this time, dad.
싫든 좋든 에디랑 사귈거에요.
I am dating Eddie
whether you like it or not.
- 에디는 내 동료야.
- 알고 있어요.
- Eddie's my partner.
- I know.
아니 몰라. 넌 경찰이 아니잖니.
But you don't. You're not a cop.
동료가 어떤 의미인지 넌 몰라.
You don't know what having a partner means.
내가 가는 곳이면, 그도 가야돼.
Wherever I go, he goes,
게다가 항상 안전한 곳도 아니란다.
and where I go isn't always safe, Iris.
난 100% 집중이 필요한 일이야.
I need to be 100% focused.
지금은...동료로서의 에디가 아니라
Now, there's a part
of me that isn't focused,
딸의 남자친구로서
that doesn't see Eddie as my partner,
집중이 안되는 부분이 있어.
but as your boyfriend.
만약 그가 다치거나 나빠진다면...
So if he gets hurt or worse,
그런데 내가 그곳에 있었어.
and I'm there,
널 어떻게 볼 수 있을까?
how am I gonna look at you?
넌 날 어떻게 볼까?
How you gonna look at me?
네게 화난게 아니란다.
Now, I'm not mad at you,
그래서 더욱 더 내게 힘든일이야.
but that's why this is so hard for me.
이해하겠니?
Do you understand?
오늘밤 다시 돌아간다.
We're going back tonight.
- 돌아가다니, 어디로?
- 박물관이지.
- Back where?
- To the museum.
다이아몬드는 여전히 그곳에 있지않은가.
That diamond isn't going to steal itself.
수퍼건이 자네 머리를 얼려버린거야, 스나트?
Super gun freeze your brain, Snart?
지금 박물관에 경찰들이 득실거릴텐데,
The museum's gonna
be crawling with police by now,
- 게다가 스트릭까지 있어.
- 이 녀석이 지켜줄거야.
- and The Streak.
- This can stop The Streak.
해치울 수 있어. 녀석의 약점을 아주 잘 알거든.
It hurt him, and I know his real weakness.
그러니 가기 싫으면 넌 빠져.
So we go, unless you want out.
우리 모두 빠질거야...살아야지.
We both want out... Alive.
그래 잘 생각하고 계획을 했단 말이지.
So you thought ahead and made a plan.
자네들에게 말한 몇가지가 있지않은가.
Least I taught you something.
그래 뭘 기다리는거야?
So what are you waiting for?
쏘라구.
Shoot me.
지금 당장 방아쇠를 당기는게 좋을거야.
You better put a bullet
in my brain right now,
그러지 않으면...
because if you don't,
너네들 모두 다시는 못볼거야.
if I ever see either one of you again...
포기하지 않는구나, 그렇지?
You don't get it, do you?
밖에 블러가 돌아다닌다구.
This blur is out there,
이젠 더 이상 센트럴시티는 네 무대가 아니야.
and Central City ain't
your playground anymore.
물론 그렇겠지.
Sure, it is.
배리?
Barry?
배리.
Barry.
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What? What are you doing?
호텔에 가 있어야지.
You should go back to your hotel.
- 잠 좀 자라구.
- 너도 자야지.
- Get some sleep.
- You should too.
내 호텔에서는 아니구...
그냥 자라는 얘기야.
Not go back to my hotel...
I meant get some sleep.
잠이 안와.
I can't.
눈을 감을 때마다 그 남자의 얼굴이 떠올라.
Every time I close my eyes,
I see that man's face.
그가 죽는 모습을 봤어.
I watched him die.
더 빨라져야해.
I have to go faster.
배리, 네 잘못도 아니잖아.
Barry, it's not your fault.
씨스코의 잘못도 아니야.
And it's not Cisco's, either.
배리, 당황스러운 것은 알겠는데,
Barry, I know you're upset,
그의 관점에서 살펴볼 필요가 있어.
but you have to look at this
from his point of view.
아니, 받아들였어.
No, I get it.
그는 날 믿지 않았던거야.
He didn't trust me.
배리, 우리가 만났을 때 말이야...
나, 올리버 그리고 디그...
Barry, when you met us...
Me, Oliver, and Dig...
기름이 잘 칠해진 활을 가지고 있었잖아.
We were this well-oiled archery machine.
하지만 처음부터 그런 것은 아니야.
But it didn't start out that way.
게다가 네 친구들처럼 밤새 모여서
얘기할 틈도 없었어.
And unlike you guys, we weren't
tossed together overnight.
하지만 우린 함께 단번에 지금까지 왔어.
We came together one at a time.
내가 그를 믿을 수 있도록 올리버가
내밀어준 손을 쳐다보는 것 보다
Believe me, it took much more
than watching Oliver
더 많은 것들이 필요했어.
do the salmon ladder to make me trust him.
다른 사람들을 위해 사는 이런 삶에
대해 직접 깨달은게 있는데...
I've seen firsthand
what this life can do to people.
외로운 여정이라는거야.
It's a lonely path.
하지만 그것보다 더 외롭게 만들지는 마.
Don't make it any
lonelier than it has to be.
꼼짝마!
Freeze!
저 문처럼 인생 끝나고 싶나?
You want to end up like that door?
잘있었니?
Hi there.
캡틴콜드를 추적할 방법을 찾았어.
I figured out a way to track Captain Cold.
이름 짓는 센스는 여전하구나.
You gotta stop naming these guys.
- 배리, 같이 들어보자꾸나.
- 어떻게?
- Barry, listen to him.
- How?
콜드건은 엔진통제장치에 의해 작동되는데
The cold gun is powered
by an engine control unit,
소형컴퓨터가 공기와 연료의 혼합비율을 조절한
a microcomputer that regulates
air-to-fuel ratios
2차냉각용액이
so the sub-cooled fluid
약실에 꽉 차지 않으면...
in the chambers don't overflow and...
- 꽝!
- 맞아.
- Explode.
- Right.
이 E.C.U는 내 태블릿으로부터 업데이트를 받는데,
This E.C.U. was receiving updates
wirelessly from my tablet.
센트럴시티의 네트워크망을 통해
If I boost the signal
using Central City's network
잘못된 업데이트 신호를 보내면,
and send a false update,
응답 신호를 받을 수 있게되고...
we'll get a ping back, and then...
스나트의 위치를 알게되는거지.
We can locate Snart.
얼마나 걸릴까?
How long will it take?
먼저 시의 전산망을 해킹해야 하니까,
First I have to hack
into the City's network,
아마도 30분은 걸릴걸?
so I don't know, 30 minutes, maybe?
내가 좀 더 빨리 해줄께.
I can do it in less than one.
해킹에 있어선 내가 가장 빠른 여자일걸.
When it comes to hacking,
I'm the fastest woman alive.
앜! 이건 내가 생각한 그림이 아닌데 말이야.
Ow! That was not as badass as I pictured.
좋아, 다 됐어.
All right, I'm in.
놀리는거야?
Are you kidding?
알았어, 업데이트 신호를 보내지.
All right, I'm sending the updates.
연결됬어.
We're connected.
삼각측정법으로 위치를 찾고 있어.
Network is triangulating the location.
찾았어. 기차역을 향해서 넬슨가
We got him. He's heading west on Nelson
서쪽으로 이동중이야.
toward the train station.
그대로 떠나게 놔둔다면, 스나트는
If he's leaving, it appears
Mr. Snart may have gotten
원하는 모든 것을 얻게 될거야.
what he came for.
우리의 마음이 함께한다면,
When we put our minds to it,
친구, 우린 천하무적이되는거야.
dude, nothing can stop us.
이런, 수신기를 꺼버리면,
Oh, you turned your ear piece off.
어떻게 대화하지?
How are we gonna talk to each other?
지금 말 섞을 기분 아니거든.
I don't feel like talking right now.
모든 대원들은 들어라,
용의자는 센트럴시 기차역으로 향하고 있다.
All available units, suspect
spotted at Central City train station.
우리가 스나트를 잡겠군요.
We got Snart.
- 여기서 지원을 기다려
- 지원을 기다리라뇨? 절대 안되죠.
- Wait here for back up.
- Wait for back up? No way.
명령일세.
That's an order.
- 배리를 도와줘야 해요.
- 배리가 말한거 들었잖아.
- You should go after Barry.
- You heard him, Felicity.
이번 일은 혼자 끝내고 싶어해.
He wants to do this alone.
물론, 그렇게 말했죠.
Of course, he said that.
그는 마음의 상처를 받았어요.
He's hurt.
당신들은 배리의 동료고 친구잖아요.
You're his team and his friends.
애로우가 뒤로 물러서라고 말할 때 마다
동전을 모아놓고 물러섰다면,
If I had a nickel for every time
The Arrow told me to back off,
올리버 퀸 만큼 갑부가 되었을 거에요.
I would be as rich as Oliver Queen,
올리버 퀸은 내가 아는 가장 부자인 사람이라서
예를 든거에요.
who I mention because he's
the richest person I know,
부자였거나 뭐 그런거죠...
or used to be.
요점은...
The point is,
무슨일이 있어도 당신 동료를
you have your partner's back
지켜야하는거에요.
no matter what.
도와줄 방법이 생각났어.
I have something that might help.
난 당신 동료지, 조수가 아니란 말이죠.
I'm your partner, not your assistant.
더 이상 도망갈 곳은 없어.
There's nowhere to run.
전에는 본 적이 없은데 말이야.
I didn't see you before.
밤에 싸돌아다니는 거 네 엄마도 아시니?
Your mom know you're out past your bedtime?
도망치고 싶다면 기차보다 더 빠른 뭔가가
If you wanted to get away
you should've taken something
있어야 할거야.
faster than a train.
내가 도망치고 싶었다면 말이야,
That's if I wanted to get away.
무장차량 사건에서 네 약점을 찾아냈지.
I've seen your weakness at the armored car,
극장에서도 그렇고,
then at the theater.
다른 사람을 구하느라 자네가 얼마나 바쁜지 보라구.
See, while you're busy saving everybody,
난 내 자신을 구하지.
I'll be saving myself.
그럼 행운을 빌지.
Good luck with that.
으악!
Ahh!
꼬마가 아주 빠르군.
Pretty fast, kid,
하지만 충분하진 않지.
but not fast enough.
고맙군.
Thank you.
뭐가?
For what?
내 승부욕을 자극해주고,
You forced me to up my game,
이 총 뿐만 아니라
not only with this gun,
이 일을 어떻게 할지 영감을 줬단 말이지.
but with how I think about the job.
아주 유익했어.
It's been educational.
총 버려.
Drop it.
시험용 콜드건이지만
This is a prototype cold gun,
네 배나 크고, 파워도 강력하지.
four times the size, four times the power.
누구랑 얘기하는지 모르겠네.
I was wondering who you were talking to.
이봐, 네 입맛에 맛는 처방전을 원한다면
Hey, unless you want a taste
of your own medicine,
그렇게 해주지.
I'd back the hell up.
너 손 떠는 것 좀 보게.
Your hands are shaking.
결코 누굴 죽이진 못하겠지.
You've never killed anyone.
캡틴콜드, 누구에게나 처음이란게 있지.
There's a first time
for everything, Captain Cold.
난 쏠거야.
I will shoot you.
네가 이겼다, 꼬마야.
You win, kid.
다시 보자꾸나.
I'll see you around.
이봐, 다이아몬드는 두고 가지.
Hey, leave the diamond.
운을 시험하진 말게나.
Don't push your luck.
쏘고 싶어도 쏠 수가 없지.
Couldn't shoot him if I wanted to.
이건 사실 LED가 다닥 다닥 붙은
This is actually
the S.T.A.R. Labs vacuum cleaner
스타랩 진공청소기거든.
with a lot of L.E.D's.
따뜻하게 해줄게.
Let's get you warm.
고마워.
Thank you.
스나트를 추적하려고 했는데,
We've been trying to track Snart,
어떻게 신호를 끊어버렸나봐.
but he must have
disconnected the signal somehow.
같이 찾게 될거야, 씨스코.
We'll find him, Cisco, together.
멋진 팀이 있구나, 배리.
You have a great team here, Barry.
팀 얘기 나와서 말인데,
나도 내 팀에 복귀해야할 것 같아.
Speaking of teams, I should
probably get back to mine.
스모크양 만나서 반가웠어요.
It was nice meeting you, Ms. Smoak.
애로우에게 안부 전해줘요.
Please extend a hello to The Arrow for us.
그렇게요.
I will.
잘가, 펠리시티.
Good-bye, Felicity.
안녕, 배리.
Bye, Barry.
기억할만한 아가씨야.
Remarkable young woman.
특별한 여자네.
She's special.
맞아요.
Yeah, she is.
씨스코,
Cisco,
다시는 그런 바보같은 짓 하지 말거라.
don't you ever do anything like that again.
내말 알아들었니?
Do you understand me?
예, 박사님.
Yes, sir.
- 안녕, 아빠.
- 그래
- Hey, dad.
- Hey.
에디 찾는다면 증거보관실에 있다.
If you're looking for Eddie,
he's in evidence.
아빠 보러 왔어요.
I am looking for you.
다시 한번 사과할게요.
I came to apologize... Again.
너 정말 매직넘버를 넘기려는구나.
You're really trying to hit
that magic number, aren't you?
아빠, 이것만은 알아주세요.
Look, dad, I just want you to know
아빠를 바라보는 이 눈빛을 바꿀 것은
that there is nothing that you could do
아무것도 없다는 거 말이에요.
that would ever change the way
that I look at you.
그리고 죄송해요.
And I'm sorry.
우리 관계가 아빠에게 어떤 영향을
I should have thought about how
줄지 생각했어야만 했어요.
it would affect you if Eddie and I...
잠깐만...
Listen...
오늘밤 스나트를 추격했을때 말이다.
Chasing down this Snart character tonight?
그와 마주쳤는데,
He had the draw on me.
에디가 날 살렸어.
Eddie saved my life.
그를 과소평가했는지도 모르지.
Maybe I underestimated him.
지금부턴 더 이상 비밀 없기에요.
From now on, no more secrets.
더 이상 비밀은 없지.
No more secrets.
- 그래, 에디 보러 가야지.
- 네.
- Well, go see Eddie.
- Okay.
늙은이 지켜줘서 고맙다고 전해라.
Thank him for watching out
for your old man.
놀래켰니?
Did I just yelp?
- 엉.
- 나도 놀랐어.
- Yeah.
- I yelped.
미안해. 놀래킬 생각은 없었어.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
날 구하러 왔다고 얘기하진 말구.
Don't tell me you're here to save me.
기차는 가장 안전한 여행방식이지.
Taking the train is still one
of the safest ways to travel.
비행기 아니었나?
I thought that was airplanes.
음...
Mm...
누군가 짝사랑하고 있다고
You remember when you told me
you had a little experience
말한 거 기억나니?
liking somebody who
didn't see you the same way?
아이리스 맞지?
That was Iris, right?
어떻게 알았어?
How did you know?
그런게 있어.
It's the little things.
그녀가 안보이면 서성거리게되고,
The way you linger on her
when she isn't looking,
연기하는 듯한 억지 웃음.
the smile you fake to play the part,
너 자신만 간직한 꿈들...
quiet dreams you keep to yourself.
너랑 올리버 처럼 말이지.
Like you and Oliver.
지피 지기인거지.
Takes one to know one.
모든게 바뀔까봐 두려워.
I'm afraid it'll change everything.
바뀌겠지.
It will,
하지만 그렇게 나쁜 것만은 아닐거야.
but maybe that's not such a bad thing.
우리가 더 나빠질게 있을까?
What is wrong with us?
우린 서로에게 완벽하잖아.
We are perfectly perfect for each other.
그래, 가질 수 없는 사람 주위를 맴돌며,
우린 여기에 앉아있네.
Yet we're sitting here,
pining for people we can't have.
반대의 성격이 떠 끌린다는
I guess what they say is true.
말이 맞는 것 같아.
Opposites do attract.
필요한게 있으면 언제든 달려갈게.
If you ever need anything,
I will race over in a heartbeat.
마찬가지야.
Same.
나도 계속 달린다면,
Well, as fast I can run,
시간이 걸리기는 하겠지만
여전히 가고 있겠지.
which might take me a while,
but I will still come.
안녕, 펠리시티.
Bye, Felicity.
안녕, 배리.
Bye, Barry.
우~후!
Whoo-hoo!
일을 끝낸지 얼마 안됐다는 건 알고,
I know it's been a while
since we pulled that job.
너랑 썩 잘 지낸 것도 아니란 거 알아.
I know it didn't go so well for you,
그리고 우리 사이가 끝났다는 것도 알지.
and I know I said we were finished.
하지만 상황이 바뀌었어.
But things have changed.
센트럴시티에서 일을 계속하고 싶은데,
If I want to keep working in Central City,
새로운 동료가 필요하단 말이지.
I'm gonna need a new kind of crew.
자네 같은 친구 말이야.
I'm gonna need someone like you.
자넨 극한 경지에서도 이겨내잖아.
You're tolerant of extremes.
자네에겐 그런 능력이 있지.
You have certain skills.
자네도 이제 뭔가 목표가 있어야겠지.
You just need some direction.
그리고 난 자네에게 그것을 줄 수 있어.
And I can give that to you.
자네 여전히 불장난 좋아하지?
You still like playing with fire?
이거 맘에 들거야.
You're gonna love this.
그래...
So...
믹, 함께 할건가? 말건가?
Are you in Mick? Or are you out?
좋아 친구, 함께 하지.
Yeah buddy, I'm in.
The FLASH
▒ REMEMBER 0416 ▒